Tyree R. Pini typini@gmail.com

Relocating to Hartford, CT

(480) 521 - 0563

www.linkedin.com/in/tyreepini

#### **Summary**

System Administrator and Data Center Technician with four years combined educational and professional experience utilizing objectoriented programming languages seeking career advancement in application and/or web development roles. An adaptable, multifaceted leader who drives innovation through creative problem solving and team collaboration.

#### **Education**

DeVry University September 2013-April 2017

Bachelor of Science: Web Development and Administration, 4.0 GPA

Chicago, IL

National Society of Leadership and Success Member

University of Nevada, Las Vegas

August 2006-August 2009

Master of Education: Curriculum and Instruction, 3.97 GPA Graduate Assistantship as Assistant Residential Life Coordinator

Brigham Young University September 1998-August 2005

Bachelor of Arts: Double Major in Media Arts Studies and Music Composition, 3.74 GPA

Provo, UT

Las Vegas, NV

### **Professional Qualifications**

- Linux OS, Oracle Advocate Certification
- Microsoft Visual Studio IDE
- Eclipse

Mac OSNetBeans

- Software Development Life Cycle
- Unit Testing and Debugging
- · Agile: Scrum, Kanban
- Proficient Languages/Libraries: Java; C++; ASP.NET in C#; SQL; JavaScript; jQuery; JSON; HTML5; CSS3
- Emerging Languages/Libraries: Node.js; React; AngularJS; Bootstrap; Python, RESTful APIs
- Adobe Creative Suite including: Dreamweaver; Photoshop; Illustrator; Premiere; After Effects; Adobe Acrobat Pro

Windows OS

## **Professional Experience**

# System Administrator / Data Center Technician

August 2017-Present

Oracle Corporation

Chandler, AZ

- Demonstrated teamwork through ongoing collaboration with Oracle Cloud Infrastructure's Knowledge Management Team analyze company needs and assess potential documents systems
- Took initiative in developing a new standard operating procedures web application for use by data center technicians worldwide using JavaScript, Bootstrap, jQuery, and AJAX
- Programmed an Auto-Ticket Generator in Node.js that makes chrono calls to Atlassian/JIRA API which increased the team's walk-through audit completion rate to 100%

### Webmaster, Volunteer Position

November 2015-December 2016

 ${\it The Alaska \ Chapter \ of American \ String \ Teacher's \ Association}$ 

Juneau, AK

- Maintained the organization's website using Squarespace and directly editing the HTML and CSS files
- Performed a complete site overhaul with new themes and content in November 2015

### **High School Teacher / Regional Music Technology Specialist**

August 2009-May 2016

Juneau School District

Juneau, AK

- Built and administered Linux Ubuntu web server for students to access class and activity related content
- Developed a 21-tab Google Sheet Application that coordinated performance schedules, rehearsals, venues, and housing for 11 schools and over 700+ participants in the annual Southeast Alaska Regional Music Festival
- Taught required and elective classes, and facilitated online learning courses which included teaching Intro to C++

### Web Development Internship

March 2016

Scottsdale, AZ

• Assisted CTO with developing and debugging of the company's website

Programmed with Eclipse using JavaScript, jQuery, HTML, and CSS

### **Work Samples**

Spark Engine

http://www.tyreepini.com/Lorem/
http://www.mrreemusic.com/
http://www.tyreepini.com/samples/movielibrary.html

http://www.squadrontowerdefense.com/ http://www.tyreepini.com/samples/masonry.html http://www.tyreepini.com/samples/article.html